

Olivier Penhoat

CTO / Director of Developer Experience

About me

I am passionate about **web development** and **IT architectures**, **experienced** in **agile** team **management** and **coaching**, able to create a **digital platform** from Think stage, to Build, Devops and Run.

CTO resolutely craftsman, capable of developing and carrying a real **product vision** in contexts with **high strategic stakes**.

In my favorite playground we often find:

JavaScript, TypeScript, NodeJS, Jest, REST, GraphQL, Docker, Redis, MongoDb, ReactJS, Zsh, Portainer, Traefik, Google Cloud

localhost:3000/en 1/10

Bio



52

☑ Email

openhoat@gmail.com



Bordeaux, France

⚠ Status

Married with 3 kids

localhost:3000/en 2/10

Skills

Deno

EXPERT

NodeJS

EXPERT

JavaScript / TypeScript

EXPERT

Docker / K8s

MASTER

ReactJS

COMFORTABLE

AngularJS

COMFORTABLE

VueJS

FAMILIAR

Redis

COMFORTABLE

MongoDB

COMFORTABLE

Neural networks / Machine Learning

COMFORTABLE

AWS, Google Cloud, Azure DevOps, Digital Ocean

A L'AISE

Shell

MASTER

REST

MASTER

GraphQL

localhost:3000/en 3/10

MASTER

Svelte

MAÎTRISE

HTML 5

MASTER

CSS 3

FAMILIAR

Scrum, Kanban

COMFORTABLE

Markdown

MASTER

Jest

EXPERT

Python, Go

FAMILIAR

GitLab CI, GitHub Actions, Azure Pipelines

MAÎTRISE

localhost:3000/en 4/10

Soft skills

Rigor & method

Active listening

Logical & analytical sense

Pedagogy

Open mind

Autonomy

Adaptability

Decision making

Honesty

Team spirit & transparency

Communication

Empathy

localhost:3000/en 5/10

Experiences

OCTO / Director of Developer Experience at Niji Bordeaux

Since 2021

- Extreme Architecture & Head of Tech of a connected mirror app / makeup experience
- Federation of internal communities of developers and architects at the national level (tech days, tech animation)
- Management of developers, support for skills development & curricula
- Building of a multi API federation platform / Unity Ads, Ironsource, Vungle, Google, TikTok, ... / NodeJS / PostgreSQL / Google Cloud
- Launch of Niji Tech program and associated blog: Niji.tech
- Implementation of a Custom Activity SalesForce Marketing Cloud NodeJS / React / Redis / AWS
- Mentoring and coaching of ReactJS / NodeJS fullstack dev teams
- Implementation of a NodeJS / MongoDb / NestJS REST API backend to collect Covid tests
- Support for technical interviews of candidates in hiring process
- · Code audits, flash audits, due diligences

CTO / Product Owner / Full stack engineer at Groupe La Poste / Branche Numérique

2015 - 2021

- Migration of the API gateway to TypeScript
- · Design and implementation of the Digiposte authentication gateway
- Creation of the CN23 mobile web application for customs declaration on tablet
- Creation of the Okapi platform, Open API of the Digital Branch of La Poste Group (developer.laposte.fr)
- · Definition of the roadmap and business models
- · Integration of billing solution, limiters, plugins
- BU Management: agile team, vision box
- Open innovation advocate
- Al training / fundamental neural networks
- · Conferences / practice / katas
- API expertise: publication of white paper API design and training

localhost:3000/en 6/10

 Stack: EcmaScript, TypeScript, GraphQL, Reactjs, Webpack, Expressjs, Gitlab pipeline, Docker, ELK, Redis

IT Architect at Groupe La Poste / Branche Numérique

2014 - 2015

- IT Architecture for Digital Confidence (Digiposte, Digiposte Pass)
- Implementations of some POCs, intra consulting
- Management of the Open API POC project for the Group
- Implementation of the laposte.io
- Full stack expertise

Consultant at Octo Technology

2013

- Technical architecture at Digiposte
- Validation of technical choices
- Coordination of performance tests
- Implementation of prototypes
- Coding of an URL shortener service for Octo
- Coding of a Dropbox / Digiposte synch webapp

Consultant Trainer at Valtech Training

2009 - 2013

- Training on over twenty courses J2EE, JS, Web, Factory Software, Quality, Security
- Areas of industry, insurance banking, service: Thalès, Dassault, NDS, Generali, CDC, Orange, ...
- R&D: Java Quality, Android, Mobile Web, Web Hacking, NodeJS, Extreme Java
- Technical coaching
- Seminars: Android, Cross-platform development, NodeJS
- · Design and production of the desktop and mobile website valtech-training.fr
- Implementation of the software factory

Software factory chief at Le Crédit Lyonnais

2008 - 2009

localhost:3000/en 7/10

- Management of a support and assistance team for tech people
- Implementation of changes in the LCL software factory
- Study on the exportability of the software factory in offshore projects
- Animation of working groups around SOA, WOA, REST
- New services and bank products chief at Crédit Agricole S.A.

2005 - 2008

- Project management Coordination of Multiple Access Banking and Mobile Internet projects
- Definition of product plans, animation of technical committees, realization of POCs, participation in Architecture Working Groups
- BAM projects, electronic statement, electronic signature, iPhone site
- RESTful SSO solution reengineering
- Technology solutions projects chief at Entenial

2001 - 2005

- Operational supervision of Web developers within the "multi-channel" pole
- Developer training in Java / Beanshell / Taglib / JSTL / MVC2
- Participation in construction work, and assistance to MOA
- Technical project chief at MDEO-Zentropy

2000 - 2001

- · Operational supervision of web projects
- · Creation of the nabab.fr website
- Design and realization of an ORM
- iNet technologies consultant at Cetal Conseil

1999 - 2000

- Advising banks (Crédit Agricole, CCF, Société Générale) in the field of iNet technologies
- · Training of internal teams in web development
- Redesign of the BancoPC site (www.ccf.fr) at a fixed price

localhost:3000/en 8/10

01/02/2023 20:29 Resume - Olivier Penhoat

Online banking project chief at Crédit Commercial de France

1999 - 2000

- Project management of Distance Banking projects within IT Studies
- Projects: BancoPC, WAP, Webroker
- Changeover to the Euro, a 2000
- Engineer at Isthme / Steria

1994 - 1996

Development of telematics and client / server applications in the banking and tertiary sector

localhost:3000/en 9/10

Education

Engineer Epita Paris

1993

Industrial computer science and artificial intelligence

BTS Lycée Jules Ferry de Versailles

1991

Industrial computer science

Bac Lycée Jules Ferry de Versailles

1989

F2 Électronique (mention bien)

Contact

□ openhoat@gmail.com

localhost:3000/en 10/10